

# Nicolas Barbey

a 36 Rue du Maréchal Foch 95120 Ermont

+(33) 6 22 61 33 94

- □ nicolas.a.barbey@gmail.com
- ☐ https://github.com/nbarbey

### À Propos

I am a staff, an architect and an experienced developer in C, Python and go.
I am specialized in software development methods.

Especially methods which emerged from the schools of software craftmanship and "extreme programming". I am experienced in the domains of identity, authentication and authorization.

I approach architecture through Domain Driven Design and software patterns that allow for continuously evolving architectures.

#### Skills

Go, Python, C TDD

Architecture DDD

Security Authn/Authz

Methods Teaming

# Experience

Staff Engineer - leboncoin, 2024 - now

Teaching and mobbing with developers

**Architect** – leboncoin, 2022 – 2024 DDD, Continuous Delivery, evolving architecture, coaching.

**Back-end developer go** – leboncoin, 2016 – 2022 Authentication, authorization, identity, scalability, methods.

**C Developer -** Exosec, 2015 - 2016 Observability application development

**C Developer -** Intersec, 2013 - 2015 High-performing application development

**Developer for image processing** – Intitek, 2012 – 2013 Embedded algorithms

**Image processing engineer** – DxO Labs, 2011 – 2012 Design of algorithms with Python

**Post-doctorat** – CEA, *2009 – 2011* 

**PhD** - CNES, 2006 - 2008

## Education

Institut d'Optique Graduate School, 2002 - 2005

**Louis-le-Grand**, 2000 - 2002

**ENCPB**, 1999 - 2000

Lycée Claude Monet, 1992 - 1999